Ima Hogg Symphony Programs Collection
University of Houston Libraries
Ima Hogg Symphony Programs Collection
1900-1978
Hogg, Ima
Ima Hogg, daughter of Texas Governor James Hogg, helped found the Houston Symphony Orchestra in 1913, and became president of the Houston Symphony Society in 1917. This collection contains materials, primarily programs, that she collected in relation to cultural events which she attended in Houston, various American cities, and abroad. The development of the Houston Symphony is well-represented through programs and newspaper clippings.
7 scrapbooks, 9 boxes; 7.8 linear feet
1969-023
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
Biographical Note
Ima Hogg, daughter of Governor James Stephen Hogg, was born in Mineola, Texas, on July 10, 1882. After graduating from the University of Texas, between 1901 and 1909 she studied music in New York, Berlin, and Vienna. She then moved to Houston, where she gave piano lessons to a select group of pupils and helped found the Houston Symphony Orchestra. She served as the first vice president of the Houston Symphony Society and became president in 1917. Ima Hogg was also involved in founding the Houston Child Guidance Center and the Hogg Foundation for Mental Hygiene. She was involved in the Philosophical Society of Texas, the Texas State Historical Survey Committee, and the Academy of Texas. She received numerous awards and honors for her philanthropic and cultural contributions to the state of Texas. On August 19, 1975, at the age of 93, Ima Hogg died of complications from a traffic accident while she was vacationing in London.
Organization History
The Houston Symphony Orchestra began when Ima Hogg sponsored a concert on June 21, 1913. Originally the orchestra was an ensemble of 33 part-time musicians with a $2,500 budget. The Houston Symphony enjoyed steady artistic growth under the direction of strong conductors, including Ernst Hoffmann (1936-47), Efrem Kurtz (1948-54), Ferenc Fricsay (1954), Leopold Stokowski (1955-61), Sir John Barbirolli (1961-67), Andre Previn (1967-69), Lawrence Foster (1971-78), Sergiu Comissiona (1979-88), and Christoph Eschenbach (1988-1999). After decades in City Auditorium or the Music Hall, the HSO moved into the visually and acoustically fine Jesse H. Jones Hall for the Performing Arts in 1966. In the years since its beginning, the orchestra has hired long-term professional musicians, played classical, pops, holiday, children's, and free concerts, offered education programs and young artist competitions, commissioned works, made recordings, broadcast concerts, and toured the United States, Europe, and Asia. During the 1998-1999 season, the orchestra consisted of 97 full-time musicians supported by a professional staff with a $18.4 million budget.
Sources
Albrecht, Theodore. Houston Symphony Orchestra. The Handbook of Texas Online. 1999. http://www.tsha.utexas.edu/handbook/online/index.html. (19 July 2000)
Bernhard, Virginia. Ima Hogg. The Handbook of Texas Online. 1999. http://www.tsha.utexas.edu/handbook/online/index.html. (19 July 2000)
Meet the Symphony: A Brief History. Houston Symphony home page. 1999. https://web-7.interliant.com/HOUSTONSYMPHONY/hsinet.nsf/website/ABriefHistory (19 July 2000)
Scope and Contents
This collection contains materials collected by Ima Hogg in relation to cultural events which she attended. Included in the collection are scrapbooks, programs, newspaper clippings, magazine articles, leaflets, brochures, other ephemeral materials, documents, and a printed book. Materials in the collection date from 1900 to 1978, with the bulk of materials falling between the years 1900 and 1964.
The majority of the programs in the collection are from symphony concerts attended by Miss Hogg, both in Houston and in various cities in the United States and Europe. The development of the Houston Symphony is well-represented in this collection through programs and newspaper clippings.
A significant portion of the programs and clippings are contained in seven scrapbooks which Miss Hogg created. Many of these scrapbooks include Miss Hogg's handwritten comments on the performances she attended.
The collection has been reorganized by format for improved access, with materials related to the Houston Symphony or other Houston cultural organizations coming first within each format category. The series are arranged as follows: Scrapbooks, Printed Book, Programs: Houston Symphony Orchestra, Houston Symphony Fund-raising/Subscription, Programs, and Clippings. The finding aid includes a complete container listing.
Subjects (Persons)
Hogg, Ima
Subjects (Organizations)
Houston Symphony Orchestra; Houston Symphony Society
Formats
Programs
Access Restrictions
Open for research.
Acquisition Information
Information of acquisition method not available.
Detailed Description
- Scrapbooks (Scrapbook 1-7)
  This series contains scrapbooks created by Ima Hogg of programs from concerts and plays she attended through the years, along with her handwritten notes on the performances. The scrapbooks are arranged in loosely chronological order. Scrapbooks 3 and 5 have extremely brittle paper and require careful handling. Scrapbook 4 includes the program for the first concert ever performed by the Houston Symphony, dated June 21, 1913.
  - Scrapbook with printed concert and opera programs from Houston, New York City, and Europe, manuscript notes, 1900-1910 (Scrapbook 1)
  - Scrapbook with printed theater and opera programs and illustrations from Houston and New York City, manuscript notes, 1901-1903 (Scrapbook 2)
  - Scrapbook with printed concert and opera programs and clippings from Houston and New York City, 1901-1917 (Scrapbook 3)
  - Scrapbook with printed concert and opera programs and tickets from Houston, New York City, and Europe, manuscript notes, 1907-1913 (Scrapbook 4)
  - Scrapbook with printed concert, opera and, theater programs from Houston, and various cities in the United States and Europe, manuscript notes, 1909-1931 (Scrapbook 5)
  - Scrapbook with printed concert, opera, and theater programs and clippings from Houston, New York City, and Europe, 1926-1930 (Scrapbook 6)
  - Scrapbook with newspaper clippings about the Houston Symphony Society, 1934-1938 (Scrapbook 7)
- Printed Book (Book 1)
  This series includes one book privately printed by the Houston Symphony Society for Ima Hogg.
  - Privately printed promotional book, 1944 (Book 1)
- Programs. Houston Symphony Orchestra (Box 1-2)
  This series contains printed programs for concerts given by the Houston Symphony Orchestra. The programs are divided into two types, and organized sequentially. Major concerts such as subscription series concerts come first, and are organized chronologically from earliest to the most recent. Other concerts such as pops or special concerts follow, and are also organized chronologically from earliest to most recent.
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Nov. 1, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Nov. 15, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Nov. 19, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Dec. 13, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Feb. 14, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Mar. 28, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Feb. 5, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Apr. 2, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Oct. 23, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts). Nov. 16, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Dec. 10, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Dec. 20, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Nov. 28, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Dec. 20, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Oct. 30, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Mar. 4, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Mar. 12, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Mar. 18, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Mar. 25, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Oct. 28, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Nov. 4, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Nov. 11, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Nov. 18, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Dec. 9, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Jan. 6, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Jan. 20, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Feb. 3, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Mar. 17, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Apr. 7, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Oct. 10, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Oct. 27, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Nov. 3, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Nov. 10, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Dec. 8, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Dec. 15, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Jan. 5, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Jan. 19, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Jan. 26, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Feb. 9, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Feb. 16, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Mar. 16, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Mar. 23, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Mar. 30, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Apr. 6, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Oct. 19, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Oct. 26, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Nov. 2, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Nov. 9, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Nov. 23, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Major concerts), Dec. 14, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Other concerts), Jan. 24, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Other concerts), Dec. 17, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Other concerts), Feb. 6, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Other concerts), Mar. 5, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Other concerts), Mar. 7, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Other concerts), Nov. 11, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Other concerts), 1950? (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Other concerts), 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Other concerts), 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Other concerts), Feb. 10, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Other concerts), Feb. 14, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Other concerts), Feb. 14, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Other concerts), Feb. 19, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Other concerts), Feb. 20, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Other concerts), Mar. 4, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Other concerts), 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Other concerts), 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Other concerts), Jan. 5, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Other concerts), 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Other concerts), 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Other concerts), 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Other concerts), Mar. 9, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Other concerts), Jan. 19, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Other concerts), Nov. 7, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Other concerts), Dec. 31, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Other concerts), 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Other concerts), May 6, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Other concerts), Nov. 10, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Other concerts), 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Other concerts), 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Other concerts), 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Other concerts), 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Other concerts), Feb. 15, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Houston Symphony Orchestra, (Other concerts), Oct. 24, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 49)
- Houston Symphony Fund-raising/Subscription (Box 2, Folder 50-61)
  This series contains promotional materials, such as pamphlets and leaflets, related to fund-raising for the Houston Symphony and subscriptions to the concert programs of the Houston Symphony. Also included in this series is a typed document comparing the symphonies of various North American cities by such factors as city population, number of concerts, budget, etc.
  - Houston Symphony Fund-raising/Subscription, October, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Houston Symphony Fund-raising/Subscription, March, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Houston Symphony Fund-raising/Subscription, 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Houston Symphony Fund-raising/Subscription, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Houston Symphony Fund-raising/Subscription, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Houston Symphony Fund-raising/Subscription, 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Houston Symphony Fund-raising/Subscription, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Houston Symphony Fund-raising/Subscription, undated (Box 2, Folder 57-61)
- Programs (Box 3-6)
  This series contains programs from various musical organizations, theatres, and music festivals other than the Houston Symphony. The organization of this series is first geographic, then according to the type of organization, with musical organizations coming before non-musical ones, and finally chronological. In this series, Houston area programs come first, followed by American programs, and finally by European programs. Within each geographic region, musical programs come first, followed by non-musical programs (primarily for theatre productions). Some of the programs are grouped by the individual organization (example: Houston Grand Opera), and some are grouped together (example: Various American Symphony Orchestras). Within each grouping, the programs are arranged chronologically.
  - The Music Guild (Houston), Apr. 10, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - The Music Guild (Houston), Oct. 2, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - The Music Guild (Houston), Dec. 4, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - The Music Guild (Houston), Apr. 23, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - The Music Guild (Houston), Sept. 24, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - The Music Guild (Houston), Dec. 10, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - The Music Guild (Houston), Apr. 22, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - The Music Guild (Houston), May 13, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - The Music Guild (Houston), May 11, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - The Music Guild (Houston), Sept. 28, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - The Music Guild (Houston), Nov. 30, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Houston Presents, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Houston Grand Opera, Mar. 19, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Houston Grand Opera, Mar. 29, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Houston Grand Opera, Dec. 5, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Houston Grand Opera, Jan. 16, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Houston Grand Opera, Apr. 2, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Houston Grand Opera, Nov. 5, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Houston Grand Opera, Apr. 8, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Carnegie Hall, Nov. 19, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Carnegie Hall, Nov. 21, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Carnegie Hall, 1939-1940 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Carnegie Hall, 1939-1940 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Carnegie Hall, Dec. 3, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Carnegie Hall, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 25-27)
  - Carnegie Hall, Mar. 25, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Carnegie Hall, Apr. 1, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Carnegie Hall, Apr. 21, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Carnegie Hall, May 12, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Carnegie Hall, May 19, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Lincoln Center, Dec. 1, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Lincoln Center, Dec. 8, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Lincoln Center, Dec. 15, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Lincoln Center, Dec. 22, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Lincoln Center, Dec. 29, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Lincoln Center, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 38-39)
  - Lincoln Center, Jan. 5, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Lincoln Center, Jan. 12, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Lincoln Center, Jan. 19, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Lincoln Center, Jan. 26, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Lincoln Center, Feb. 2, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Lincoln Center, Feb. 9, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Lincoln Center, Feb. 16, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Lincoln Center, Feb. 23, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Lincoln Center, Mar. 1, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Lincoln Center, Mar. 8, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Lincoln Center, Mar. 15, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Lincoln Center, Mar. 22, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Lincoln Center, Mar. 29, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Lincoln Center, Apr. 5, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Lincoln Center, Apr. 12, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Lincoln Center, Apr. 19, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Lincoln Center, Apr. 26, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Lincoln Center, May 3, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Lincoln Center, May 10, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Various American Symphony Orchestras, 1900-1901 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Various American Symphony Orchestras, Nov. 1939 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Various American Symphony Orchestras, 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 3-4)
  - Various American Symphony Orchestras, Oct. 1946 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Various American Symphony Orchestras, 1949-1950 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Various American Symphony Orchestras, 1950-1951 (Box 4, Folder 7-8)
  - Various American Symphony Orchestras, Apr. 1951 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Various American Symphony Orchestras, 1952-1953 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Various American Symphony Orchestras, 1954-1955 (Box 4, Folder 11-12)
  - Various American Symphony Orchestras, Mar. 1956 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Various American Symphony Orchestras, 1956-1957 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Various American Symphony Orchestras, Mar. 1957 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Various American Symphony Orchestras, Mar. 1963 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Various American Symphony Orchestras, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Various American Recitals, August, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Various American Recitals, April, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Various American Recitals, March, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Various American Recitals, Dec. 1962 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Various American Recitals, Jan. 1963 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Various American Recitals, March, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Various American Recitals, April, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Various American Recitals, Nov. 1963 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Various American Recitals, April, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 26-27)
  - Various American Recitals, Nov. 1964 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Various American Recitals, undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Various American Theatres, Dec. 1939 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Various American Theatres, 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Various American Theatres, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Various American Theatres, August, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 33-35)
  - Various American Theatres, January, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Various American Theatres, May, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 37-38)
  - Various American Theatres, July, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Various American Theatres, undated (Box 4, Folder 40-42)
  - Bayreuther Festival, July 19-Aug. 31, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
  - Bayreuther Festival, July 31-Aug. 21, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Bayreuther Festival, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 4-10)
  - Bayreuther Festival, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Edinburgh International Festival, Aug. 20, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 12-13)
  - Edinburgh International Festival, Aug. 21, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Edinburgh International Festival, Aug. 22, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Edinburgh International Festival, Aug. 25, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Edinburgh International Festival, Aug. 20-Sept. 9, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Edinburgh International Festival, Aug. 21-Sept. 9, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 18-20)
  - Edinburgh International Festival, Aug.21-Sept.10, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Holland Festival, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 22-30)
  - Munich Festival, July 20-Aug. 29, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Munich Festival, Aug. 12-Sept. 11, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Salzburg Festival, July 30-Aug. 31, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Salzburg Festival, July 22-Aug. 30, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Salzburg Festival, July 25-Aug. 31, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Salzburg Festival, Aug. 2, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Salzburg Festival, Aug. 12, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Salzburg Festival, Aug. 17, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Salzburg Festival, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 39-43)
  - Salzburg Festival, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 44-50)
  - Salzburg Festival, July 24-Aug. 31, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Salzburg Festival, July 23-Aug. 31, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Salzburg Festival, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Salzburg Festival, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Bayeriche Staatstheater, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
  - Bayeriche Staatstheater, 1936 - 1937 (Box 6, Folder 3-4)
  - Bayeriche Staatstheater, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Theatre National de l'Opera, 1928 - 1929 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Theatre National de l'Opera, 1929 - 1930 (Box 6, Folder 7-8)
  - Theatre National de l'Opera, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Theatre National de l'Opera, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 10-11)
  - Various European Performances, 1923 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Various European Performances, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Various European Performances, 1936 - 1937 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Various European Performances, August 1950 (Box 6, Folder 15-17)
  - Various European Performances, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Various European Performances, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Various European Performances, Sept. 1955 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Various European Performances, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Various European Performances, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Various European Performances, 1956? (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Various European Performances, 1957 - 1958 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Various European Performances, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 25-26)
  - Various European Performances, May 1961 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Various European Performances, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Various European Performances, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Various European Performances, undated (Box 6, Folder 30-36)
  - Various European Theatres, 1929 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Various European Theatres, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 38)